

Alejandro Berrío Marín

✓✓✓✓✓✓

+57 313 708 1557

alejo86a@gmail.com

Medellín / Colombia

linkedin.com/in/alejo86a

twitter.com/alejo86adev

github.com/alejo86a

Backend developer

SKILLS javascript typescript nodejs expressis java Java EE Html/css Angular Angularjs Php/laravel SCRUM Scala Ionic GIT

EDUCATION

Systems Engineering

ITM (Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano) 7° semester (actual)

Diploma Leadership in an age of disruption

CSUN (California State University Northridge) 2022

Diploma course in advance architecture with microservices and devops

UdeA (Universidad de Antioquia) 2018

Systems Engineering

UdeA (Universidad de Antioquia) 8° semester (in pause)

Systems Technique

SENA (Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje)
2011

ABOUT ME

I am a developer passionate about new technologies who loves to learn all kinds of technologies in a self-taught way. Entrepreneurship lover from my own personal projects to my work experience. Obsessed with meeting goals quickly under the principles of quality, extensibility, security, reusability, and code readability

EXPERIENCE

Publicis Global Delivery (prodigious)

Senior Principal Software Engineer/San Francisco, California / 2021-2022

- Backend development mainly with nodejs and other technologies such as java and react.
- working in internals projects at knex, springboot, react, strapi, azure.
- talent interviewer with nodejs profile.
- Interview new candidates for the position of senior software engineer in nodeis.

BairesDevSoftware

Development Engineer / San Francisco, California / 2021

outsourcing and software development company that allowed me to be part of two interesting projects

- Instructure: as a backend developer in nodejs .
- waitr app: as a backend developer in nodejs and devops.

Rapicredit

software engeneer / Bogotá, Colombia / 2020-2021

fintech startup in charge of making small loans to unbanked people.

- Development frontend with angular in charge of implementing the best practices in the development.
- Development backend creation of endpoint with java spring boot and the drools rule manager.

Intermediate backend developer Rappi S.A.S./Bogota, Colombia/2018-2020

 Development of rappiPay an alternative to send, receive money or pay without using a bank card

Development consultant

SETI S.A.S./Medellín, Colombia/2016-2020 Full stack developer in the following projects:

- Develop a platform for the management of proposals, company commercials, sales and follow up projects. This project was developed in Angular, Java EE and Oracle.
- Platform for the quote and sale of car insurance and company insurance developed in GuideWire, Angular and Scala.

CERTIFICATES

IBM Cloud basics on platzi (2018)

Basic of architecture, micro services and artificial intelligence as well as the installation and IBM cloud application deployment.

SCALA intensive course (2018)

Dictated by seven4n.

Jenkins CI and DevOps (2017)

Master Jenkins Build and Test Automation in 2 Hours. Hand-on DevOps, CICD, Jenkins Pipeline, Jenkins on AWS.

Call for discovery of apps.co (2016)

Which I was a finalist and I acquired Marketing insights, customer discovery, and some talks on software development mainly in doing a quick MVP.

Startup weekend Medellín "INTERNET OF THINGS" (2015)

Event of entrepreneurship in which for 3 days of continuous work in the city of Medellín the aim was to develop an innovative idea within an interdisciplinary team.

Fintech challenge (2015)

Event of bank entrepreneurship in which for 3 days of continuous work in the city of Bogota the aim was to develop an innovative idea within an interdisciplinary team.

Application development course for IOS (2013)

Dictated by arunovo and rutaN.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Freelancer

Freelancer/Colombia/ 2012-2016

Develop web pages in HTML and CSS to promote and show small products and services of small companies.

- Design and layout.
- Logo construction and photo editing.
- Deploy and maintain the website in time.

Founder and CEO

Peiname.co/Colombia/ 2016

- Founder of my own start up.
- Marketing.
- Customer discovery.
- MVP development (android and ios app).